Wrege, Charles D. Collection of History of Management Documents 6014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Original Documents including letters from Barth to Keppele Hall, Thompson, and others.. (Box 2)
  - Booklet - R.W. Bixby Inc. - Buffalo, NY "A Confidential Service" [employment agency] (found in Keppele Hall's papers when he died in 1926m CDW) (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Keppele Hall Lamson & Sessions Co. Cleveland, Ohio Shop Chart Feb. 7, 1924 Original (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Keppele Hall - Original - Balance Sheets of Lamson & Sessions Co. 12-31-1925 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Mrs. Keppele Hall to Mr. and Mrs. C Wrege May 25, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - 1905 Paper Negatives of Midvale Steel (2 views) (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Apprenticeship Papers - Midvale - Originals, 1910-1916 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Midvale Book on Employees - 1892-1913 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Midvale Hempenbstall Centennial Booklet 1867-1967 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    Original Booklet
  - Original Recollections of F. W. Taylor (2 sheets typed) from John P. Mudd File Midvale Steel - Plus Copies, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Steel Production (in tons) at Midvale 1908-1951 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Data on Passaic Metal Ware Co. & Scientific Management 1989 (installed Taylor System 1911) (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Includes xerox copies of photos
  - Passaic Metal Ware (Copies of Originals) from Mrs. England, Passaic, NJ 1989 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    Copies of Originals
  - Original Report of Cost Keeping Under the Taylor System at Tabor Mgmt. Co. (no date but 1912) (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Horace K. Hathaway "Elementary Time Study" Booklet 0 1912 (Tabor Mgmt. Co) (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - National Electric Light Association 1916 on Taylor (in envelope) Original (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Charles Ellet Jr. - 1839 Map of German Town (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Manufacturing Investment Co. Appleton Division - Data from Mr. E. Rodhe 1990 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Review of "A Piece Rate System: by Taylor, American Machinist-July 4, 1895, p. 530 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - C.E. Knoeppel and Emergency Fleet Corporation, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    Copies of Management Plans from National Archives -Hard to Get* Difficult to get copies from archives in 1982
  - Dolphin Jute Mills Work Data 1911-Original (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - 2 (Close Up) Negatives of F.W. Taylor at Midvale Steel mode at Cornell Univ. in 1991 to Possibly Identifying Taylor from Shape of His Ears (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Enlargement of F.W. Taylor to Identify Ears for Comparison with Data Photos (These Photos Taken at Midvale Steel (Box 2, Folder 97)
    No dates
  - Pennsylvania Gazette, Jan., 1947 with Data on F.W. Taylor Management Laboratory - Original (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Fraquar - Memo to Dean of Harvard Business School on Taylor Systems - Oct. 8, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Hartley C. Wolle Notes on Bethlehem Steel 1891-1895 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    1964
  - Data on Newton Machine Tool Works (Box 2, Folder 101)
    be phila (owned by Emhart Corp. Farmingdale, Conn) no date
  - Hawthorne Report on "Cost" (1912?) Original Report (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - The Farrel Foundry and Machine Co. Ansonia, Conn. On "Relative to Cost Numbers" - Original Booklet by H. K. Hathaway (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - "Scientific Management and it's Relation to the Foundry Industry", 1915 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    Horace K. Hathaway August 14, 1915- (concerns Taylor System Elementary)
  - F. W. Taylor-"Description of Entries Made by Bookkeeper in Connection with 'Cost'", 1911 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    (Original Probably prepared by H. K. Hathaway - 1911) CDW 11/9/91
  - Computer Analysis of Pig Iron Study - 1982 Originals (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - N-Files Newsletter - Oct. 1978 on F.W. Taylor (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - "Search for Schmidt" American Cemetery Sept. 1964 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    Henry Noll and Taylor
  - Original Onion Skin - of Unloading Coal, March 13m 1892 at Appleton, Wisc. From Everette Rhode of Consolidated Paper -Through Ron Greenwood (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Letter from H.L. Gantt to P.W. Davenport July 29, 1901 (3 pages) (on Ingots) from S.E. Thompson Files 1977 Originals (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Cooke and Gantt Letter, 1899-1908 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    Gantt Letter are originals
  - Gantt Letter 1901 Originals (Box 2, Folder 112)
    1. to Davenport July 26, 1901 2. to Taylor July 29, 1901, Aug 2, 1901 3. to Chambers July 26, 1901 * originals from Peter (Justice) Collins West Grove, PA 19390
  - Henry L. Gantt to F.W. Taylor Handwritten 9/11/1901 Original (Box 2, Folder 113)
    Taylor to Gantt June 14, 1909, Gantt ti Taylor August 20, 1912 *Originals from Peter (Justice) Collins descendent of George M. Justice father of Phillip Justice (related to Taylor & Mitchell Families) of 797 Wickson Road West Grove, PA 19390 CDW
  - Peter Collins Letters on Justice Family 1990 Originals (Box 2, Folder 114)
    Peter Collins, 797 Wickson Road, West Grove, PA 19390
  - Taylor to Gantt Sept.4, 1914 - Original Carbon (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Survey of Polk City Directory of Hoboken 1878-1883 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    Mrs. Hartye 10/29/89, Taylor 11/22/88 * Search for addresses of Gantt, Taylor etc. while students at Stevens
  - Percy S. Brown Correspondence with George Sweet Gibb of Harvard Business School on Proposed History of Taylor Society - Sept. 8, 12, 16, 1952 and Other Letters Originals (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Taylor Society 1926 Original Nucleus of a Management Library (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - 1941 Meeting of Society for Advancement of Management (Thompson Papers) Original (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Washington DC Chapter of Society for Advancement of Mgt. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    Mgt. Books on Display - LIST Original
  - Graphic Analysis of Scientific Management by H.S. Person - 1944 Original (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Bulletin of Engineering Dept. of The National Electric Lamp Association Jan. 14, 1907 from Snow Original (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - "Lizzie Likes Her Job" Independent, Nov. 6, 1920 (on Feiss Plant) (Box 2, Folder 123)
- Original Documents. Harlow Person, Thompson, and other letters and photos of Taylor and others, people in trains, and the Manufacturing Investment Co.. (Box 3)
  - Lester Kaighn Study of Sanford Thompson-1/25/1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sanford Thompson Data, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Raymond P/ Hill and Robert Bunsen Wolf (Wolf & Scientific Management), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sanford Thompson-Harry Hopf Letters 1/16/1935 (paper 1 & 3). S.E. Thompson (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Barth to Thompson-9/28/1933 on Material Stored in 3rd Floor of "Boxly" (original letter at Cornell) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Original Letter to William B. Wolf 1914, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Marion Beckwith (Sanford Thompson's Daughter) on Thompson and Thompson Election Nov. 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    In "Sanford Thompson Manuscript pages" folder
  - Taylor Book-Sanford Thompson Letters 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pages from Sanford Thompson Manuscript (Box 3, Folder 9)
    In "Sanford Thompson Manuscript pages" folder (in campus envelope)
  - Sanford Thompson Letter with Henry P. Kendall - 12/29/32 on Al Ford and his "Hoboes"-Taylor Society, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Copy of 1800's handwritten journal, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Harry Hopf Letter1/16/1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Page 248 of Thomson Letter book #9 Original, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thompson on Taylor-March 18, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Data on Sanford Thompson-Taylor Experiment Hours in Newton MASS, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Taylor-Thompson 1906, 1906-1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Taylor Security - Sanford Thompson Letters 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Taylor-Thompson Letters 1908 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Photograph of Factory from Sanford Thompson Papers, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Letters Between Mrs. FW Taylor and Sanford Thompson 1935-1948 and Feiss Cartoon 1925, 1925-1948 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Sanford Thompson Letters from Letter Press Books1908 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sanford Thompson-Taylor Letters 1896-1907 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Taylor to Thompson - July 17, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - F.W. Taylor Telegram to Thompson March 31 1908-on meeting Gilbrath-ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Original Taylor Telegraph message to Thompson on Gilbrath 3/31/1908
  - Sanford Thompson to M.L. Cooke on letter to President Hoover-July 18, 1932 ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Harlow Person (ORIGINAL) memo to Sanford Thompson on Financial Crisis of Taylor Society May 24, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Note from Harlow Person to Sanford Thompson on "Financial Problem" of Taylor Society - 5/24/32 Copy of Original, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Two Letters between Stanford Thompson and E.S. Shulski Nov 3- Nov 16, 1938 ORIGINALS (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Letter from War Dept. 1918 (Dec. 17, 1918) to Sanford Thompson ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Copies of Letters in Thompson Letter Books (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Milestones of Management, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Modern Foremanship (no date) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    La Salle Extension University
  - Otto S. Beyer, Jr. Letter to Keppele Hall Jan. 7, 1926 ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Southern District National-Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers - Jan. 8, 1920-on meeting-R. Fleiss Files (Notes by Keppele Hall) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Original - Contains letter to Tracy Copp Jan. 10, 1920
  - Leffingwell-Ream Co. 1921-Flyer on "How to Manage" ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Urwick letter to Mayo 10/25/1944 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Henry R. Towne to Carl Barth May 18, 1920 on Science of MST first formulated by Taylor ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Unpublished Data on Henry R. Towne Jan. 9, 1958 Towne-Taylor ORIGINALS (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Old DATA on Yale & Towne in Philadelphia (1897) ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Lyndall Urwick Correspondence 1957 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Letter from Urwick, Orr-London January 9, 1958-misc (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Urwick Letters on Mayo 1957 - ORIGINALS (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Robert Valentine Brochure ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Illustrations (photos) for Canal Museum paper on Taylor at Midvale, 1868-1887 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Photograph and negative of Maunsel White (save for High Speed Steel) (Box 3, Folder 45)
    ORIGINAL
  - Negative of Feiss and Hawthorne (Lined Screen) (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Original 1929 Photo of Richard A. Feiss from Mrs. Feiss (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gilbreth Medical Photos (Box 3, Folder 48)
    non date
  - On Gilbreth Photos from Robert Walp-County Way Medical Library 8/28/1985 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1936 Floor Photos of Madison Paper Co. 1982 Photos of Madison Paper Co, 1936-1982 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Manufacturing Investment Co Photos February 25, 1891 November 1899 Manufacturing Investment Co Taylor, 1891-1899 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Madison Maine Mgt. Investment Co Jan. 28, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - 1889 Photographs of Building of the Madison Mill of the Mgt Investment Co Madison, Maine (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Originals Photos of Mgt. Investment Co Madison, Maine, Plus 1982 Photos, 1920-1982 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - ORIGINAL Map of Manufacturing Investment Co Madison. Maine 1907 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Two Photographs of Construction of Manufacturing Investment Co Madison, Maine - 1889 ORIGINALS (Box 3, Folder 56)
    #1 Digesters #2 Main Building
  - Flood at Madison, Maine (Manufacturing Investment Co) April 19, 1936 ORIGINAL PHOTOS (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Tintype of Henry Noll 1899 ORIGINAL (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Original Tin Type
  - Copies of Original Photos of Henry Noll, House in Bethlehem, PA and Noll & Wife Plus R. Feiss Clothescraft Shops Operators Playing Ball, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Color Slides & Negatives of Henry Noll Site of His House & Concrete Horses in Bethlehem (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Passaic Metal Ware Photos - Copies of Originals 1989 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    Copies of Passaic Metal Ware Photos
  - Passaic Metal Ware & Brighton Mills Photos & Maps Taylor (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Original- Photo of FW Taylor from Mrs. Richard Feiss (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - #6014 Bx 3 ORIGINAL - Photo of FW Taylor from Mrs. Richard A. Feiss -15 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Original Photos of Tavor Mgt Co. Mula & Plimpton Press (1911), Norwood, Mass (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Management History Photos, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - "Experimental Housekeeping Station" Colonial, NJ Photos copies of originals, 1909-1916 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    see CD Wrege Paper of 1981 inside Folder on Scientific Mgt & "Domestic Engineering-1909-1916"
  - Five 35mm Slides of Mr. Pattison's Experimental Housekeeping Station Colonia, NJ (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Original Photos of Dr. Jan Don Ball early industrial psychiatrist 1916-1922 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    ([unknown word] of his associate chief August Vollner of Berkley, Police Dept. 1918
  - Photo of Mary Jarrett in office - circa 1915 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Photos of Machines in High Falls, NY (from in Sanford Thompson Files) (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Photos of Dolphin Jute Mills 1990 (Paterson, NJ) (Box 3, Folder 72)
    *site of early industrial illumination test CDW
  - Original Photograph of William Daniel Basley (Taylor Basley) (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Photograph of String Control Board 1921 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    End result system Codman Hospital
  - Daniel Drawbaugh Telephone - Photo (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Negative & Print of Dr. Isaac Adams House Annisquam, MA (with his 1882 glassbrick basement windows) (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Keppele Hall Photograph 1926 (from Mrs. Keppele Hall, 11/23/60) (Taylor), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Original Photo of Horace King Hathaway plus copy Negative (Taylor) (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Photos from Presentation (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Thompson's original 1900 and 1902 letter press books, and his original 1896 notebooks.. (Box 4)
  - Panel Switch Manual - Photocopy, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Proposed Plan of Organization of the Needle Trades Conference in America, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hughes, Florence. Sociological Work The New Jersey Zinc Co., 1914 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commons, John R. Lizzie Likes Her Job, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Taylor Society Meetings, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - What is the Taylor Society?, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Barth-Feiss Letter - Oct 27 1919 ORIGINAL (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1901 Agreement with Theodore Shaffer (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Feiss and Robert Bruere 1934-1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mrs. Richard A. Feiss Talk on "Personal Relationships, Women & Girls at Cloth crafts" 1919 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Original Manuscript
  - Original Letters (Carbons) -letters to Henry P. Kendall on Alford and his "hoboes" 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photograph of Feiss Plant from Clothcraft March, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fatigue from the Economic Standpoint: P.S. Florence (originals) 1916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carbon Letter to Mrs. R. Feiss on Feiss Papers Arriving Ok 9/9/1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sanford Thompson Letters on Bethlehem and to Gilbreth 1901-1902 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Standing Order for Maintenance Department" Eton, Crane and Pike Co (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - R. A. Feiss Data (includes paper "Managing The Boss" Harpers, Dec 1926, pp120-126 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Society for Advanced Management "production for Victory" with Person, Thompson, Farquhar-2-24-42, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Taylor to Gilbreth 4-27-08, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Taylor to Gilbreth April 27, 1908 ORIGINAL
  - Letters from Argyris, Maslow, Burtt 1967 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    (Mrs.) Dora S. Ginsberg Personnel Adm 365 -Dr. CDWrege - Original Letters 1967 Argyris, Abraham Maslow, Harold Burtt (Mumterbey Assistant present when he died in 1916
  - R.A. Feiss Publications, 1915-1943 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sanford Thompson 1896 Notebooks on Methods of Performing Tasks (2) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Letters: Jan-Dec 1902 No. 9 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Letter: Jan 1900 - Dec 1901 No. 8, 1900-1901 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Panel Mechanical Machine-Switching Manual 1939 David Miller's DVD (Box 5)
  - Panel Mechanical Machine-Switching Manual 1939 David Miller's DVD (Box 5, Folder 1)